VINCENT J. SCHAEFER PAPERS (UA902.010) 1891-1993
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- General Electric- Non-Project Cirrus, 1891-1993; 1; 21.0
  - Reports & Publications by Others-- Non-General Electric, 1901-1953; 1978; 1988; 1993; Undated; 1.9
    - "Earthquake Notes" Donn and Jennemann, 1953 March (Box 33, Folder 44)
    - "Calculations on drop Size Growth and Supersaturation on Air in an Icing Wind Tunnel" Myron Tribus and J. Klein, 1953 March (Box 33, Folder 45)
    - "Eidgenoessisches Volkswirtschaftsdepartment", 1953 March (Box 33, Folder 46)
    - "On the Growth of Snow Flake and Graupel" C. Magono, 1953 March (Box 33, Folder 47)
    - "Recent Studies on Tropical Meteorology", 1953 March (Box 33, Folder 48)
    - "Evidence of Man-Made Climatic Change" Irving Krick, 1953 April (Box 33, Folder 49)
    - "Cloud Seeding May Turn Wheels from P.G & E from Electric Light & Power", 1953 April (Box 33, Folder 50)
    - "Electric-Microscope Study of Atmospheric Condensation Nuclei" Kuroiwa, 1953 April (Box 33, Folder 51)
    - "Extended Use of the Double Mass Curve" Carroll F. Merriam, 1953 April 30 (Box 33, Folder 52)
    - "A Balloon Fog Meter and the Vertical Distribution of Liquid Water Contents in Lower Atmosphere" Kuroiwa and Kinosita, 1953 April (Box 33, Folder 53)
    - "The Turbulent Diffusion of Fog Water near the Ground and the Fog-Preventing Effect of an Artificial Model Forest" Kuroiwa, 1953 April (Box 33, Folder 54)
    - "Summary Evaluation of Cloud Operations in Cuba", 1953 April (Box 33, Folder 55)
    - "Wind Force on a Conifer Tree and the Quantity of Fog Water Thereby Captured" Zyungo Yosida and Daisuke Kuroiwa, 1953 April (Box 33, Folder 56)
    - "Marine Meteorology-Some Results of a Trade Cumulus Cloud Investigation" Joanne Starr Malkus, 1953 May (Box 33, Folder 57)
    - "Tomorrow's Weather", 1953 May (Box 33, Folder 58)
    - "Dallas Cloud Seeding Operations" Irving P. Krick, 1953 June 09 (Box 33, Folder 59)
    - "It's Done with Mirrors" Matthews, C.F., 1953 Summer (Box 33, Folder 60)
    - "Distribution of Solar Energy over the United States" I.F. Hand, 1953 July (Box 33, Folder 61)
    - "Turbulence in Clouds as a factor in Precipitation" East and Marshall, 1953 July (Box 33, Folder 62)
    - "A Theory of Snow Crystal Habit & Growth" J.S. Marshall M.P. Langleben, 1953 July (Box 33, Folder 63)
    - "The Distribution of Rain in Tropical Storms" C.S. Ramage, 1953 August (Box 33, Folder 64)
    - "Rockets and Rainmaking" Leon Slawecki, 1953 September (Box 33, Folder 65)
    - "Uniformly Conductive Surfaces", 1953 September (Box 33, Folder 66)
    - "Quarterly"-Tech. Report #2, 1953 September 15 (Box 33, Folder 67)
    - "Maximum Evaporation Rates of Water Droplets Approaching Obstacles in the Atmosphere Under Icing Conditions"-Tech. Note #3024 Herman H. Lowell, 1953 October (Box 33, Folder 68)
    - Weatherwise Magazine, 1953 October (Box 33, Folder 69)
    - "Atmospheric Oscillation & Related Synoptic Patterns"- Tech. Report on Meteorology #1, D. William, R. Rommer, F. Press, M. Ewing, 1953 November (Box 33, Folder 70)
    - "Sea Salt Nuclei Studies", 1953 December (Box 33, Folder 71)
    - "Algal Culture" (J.S. Berlin), 1953 July 15 (Box 33, Folder 72)
    - "Radar Observation of Rain from Non-Freezing Clouds" R.S. Styles and F.W. Campbell, 1953 (Box 33, Folder 73)
    - "On the Ice Crystals Nuclei and other Substances found in Snow Crystal" K. Isono, ca. 1953 (Box 33, Folder 74)
    - "The Influence of Volcanic Dust on Precipitation" K. Isono and M. Komabaysi, ca. 1953 (Box 33, Folder 75)
    - "Early History of Cloud Seeding" B.S. Havens, J.E. Jiusto and B. Vonnegut, 1978 (Box 33, Folder 76)
    - "Langmuir-Blodgett Films" V.K. Agarwal, 1988 June (Box 33, Folder 77)
    - "Sky Island: A View of Vrooman's Nose," Laura Ten Eyck, 1993 March 25 (Oversized 2, Folder 3)
    - Air Pollution Conference Report, Undated (Box 33, Folder 78)
    - "A Comparison of Icing Conditions on Mt. Washington with Those Encountered in Flight" W.E. Howell, Undated (Box 33, Folder 79)
    - "Concentration of Ice Crystal Nuclei under Various Weather Conditions" W.E. Hubert and H.J. Wells, Undated (Box 33, Folder 80)
    - "The Formation of Snow Crystals: Results of Snow Investigation at Aerological Observatory at Friedrichschafen- 1940-1943" E. Wall, Undated (Box 33, Folder 81)
    - "Economic Significance of Snowfall and Snow Retention on Western Watersheds" W.W. McLaughlin, Undated (Box 33, Folder 82)
    - "Frazil Ice Trouble at Chicago's New Filtration Plant" W.W. DeBerard, Undated (Box 33, Folder 83)
    - "Indian Studies Rain Making as Aid to Food Production", Undated (Box 33, Folder 84)
    - "La Pluie Artificielle" J. Roulleau, Undated (Box 33, Folder 85)
    - "Meteorological Conditions at Selected Airports in Canada Newfoundland and Labrador", Undated (Box 33, Folder 86)
    - "Meteorological Problems in Forecasting Mountain Waves" DeVer Colson, Undated (Box 33, Folder 87)
    - "On the Methodology of Evaluating Cloud Seeding Operations" Jeeves, LeCam, Neyman, Scott, Undated (Box 33, Folder 88)
    - "Periodic Fluctuations in the Ohio Basin Moisture Balance" W.E. Hubert and H.J. Wells, Undated (Box 33, Folder 89)
    - "The Problem of Artificial Control of Rainfall on the Globe" Tor Bergeron, Undated (Box 33, Folder 90)
    - "Selection of Meteorological Quantities for the Design of Thermal Ice-Prevention Equipment" A.R. Jones and W. Lewis, Undated (Box 33, Folder 91)
    - "The Water Equivalent of Snow on Ground" C.A. Mixer, Undated (Box 33, Folder 92)
- General Electric- Project Cirrus, 1943-1954; 1981; Undated; 2; 9.5
  In 1952, General Electric published its own “History of Project Cirrus”, compiled by Barrington Havens of G.E.’s public relations department. In his introduction, he writes that “[Project Cirrus] was very complex, with a number of subdivisions associated with the main activity. Some of these subdivisions ran consecutively, some operated in parallel, and others intertwined or branched off in variously divergent directions.” This preface is relevant to Schaefer’s own collection of materials because the “intertwined” nature of Cirrus itself, as well as its roots in Schaefer and Langmuir’s previous work, sometimes made it difficult for the archivist to separate Project Cirrus documents from materials that related to cloud seeding efforts but were not strictly part of the work done under the government contract that defined Project Cirrus.
  The archivist made every attempt to be strict with materials placed into the Project Cirrus series, using dates, acknowledgements to the military, and the Army Signal Corp’s own stamp to help identify documents as Project Cirrus when needed. Researchers may find it helpful to consult the cloud seeding materials in Series #1 for items documenting the events that led to the project’s founding.
  Project Cirrus bloomed from multiple experiments that converged late in 1946. Vincent Schaefer and Irving Langmuir did extensive work for the United States military during World War II. Among their projects was the issue of precipitation static interfering with U.S. Airforce pilots' ability to fly and land safely. (See Series #1, General Electric) Their efforts to deal with the problem took them to the peak of New Hampshire's Mount Washington, where Schaefer and Langmuir observed behaviors of snow and ice crystals that were relevant to their current work but also gave them ideas for future research regarding supercooled water droplets.
  When their contracts with the U.S. military ran out shortly after World War II, Schaefer and Langmuir continued studying behaviors of snow and ice particles in earnest. Schaefer discovered that he could use a type of special plastic called Formvar to capture and preserve snowflakes, some of which can be found in Series #1. These experiments led Schaefer to investigate further the behavior of particles in cloud formations. On a hot July day in 1946, while working with a cold chamber, Schaefer accidentally discovered that the use of dry ice in a supercooled cloud would form instant ice crystals. Drs. Irving Langmuir and Bernard Vonnegut added their expertise to the process, working with silver iodide as well as dry ice. In no time they worked out the potential effects of their discovery on weather modification, and the seeds of Project Cirrus were firmly planted.
  Ultimately, on November 13, 1946, Schaefer led a successful cloud seeding expedition over Mount Greylock in Massachusetts. His efforts convinced the U.S. military to sign a contract with General Electric yet again early in 1947. This time, it was a mutual agreement between G.E., the Army Signal Corps of Engineers, the Air Force, and the Office of Naval Research. The government hoped that fruitful cloud seeding experimentation would open doors for agricultural success and even improved safety for the people of the United States. The project sponsored well over 150 flights as well as ground operations, with 1948-1950 being the major years for flights conducted. Besides basic cloud seeding work, they also experimented with hurricane seeding and wildfire fighting in the fall of 1947. The project wrapped up in September 1952 when the Airforce pilots began to be called away to Korea, and the G.E. team decided they had gone as far as they could with their work.
  This series is divided into three parts: flight data and research, subject files, and reports and publications. Each one highlights various aspects of G.E.'s efforts to work with the military as they explored cloud seeding options in the late 1940s and early 1950s.
  - Flight Data and Research, 1946-1953; Undated; 2.1
    Arranged Alphabetically
    This subseries contains materials on specific flights, though the availability of data ranges from a single page for some flights to multiple pages with photos for other flights. Each one is labeled by flight number, where it took place, what operation was performed, and on what date. There are also files on research efforts that took place on the ground and in the lab, including charts, diagrams, weather observations, and research notebooks. Photographs include particular flights, most of which feature aerial cloud views, but there are also general photos that were not labeled by Schaefer or his colleagues.
    Researchers will also find documents on two extra Project Cirrus missions, one dealing with Hurricane King and the other with Operation Red. Both pursuits took place in the fall of 1947. The former related to cloud seeding a hurricane in order to expend its energy before it made landfall while Operation Red focused on cloud seeding over wildfires in New England. The Hurricane King effort is not to be confused with the Hurricane King of 1950; the Project Cirrus crew named the 1947 hurricane on their own but did not have a title from official weather bureaus.
    Please note that Schaefer's preliminary materials on cloud seeding, as well as data and photos from his 1946 cloud seeding flights, are located in Series #1 because they took place before the official creation of Project Cirrus in 1947.
    - Adiabatic Diagrams, 1950 April-1950 December (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - B-17G Airplane- Axis and Viewing Angles, 1947 September 30 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Characteristics of a Good Crystalizer, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Chart: Corrections for Photograph Horizon, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Charts, Graphs, and Formulas, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Climate Research, 1949-1952 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Cloud Observations and Data- "Constellation Flight", 1950 November 04 (Map-tube 1)
    - Cloud Seeding Notes and Data, 1947-1951 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
    - Cloud Seeding Notes and Data, 1949-1952 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Diagrams: Seeding Tracks and Stratiform Clouds, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Discharge Correlations of Gaging Stations, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Experimental Meteorology Data, 1946-1949 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Flight Notes, 1948 February 19; 1948 February 20 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Flight Summary-Kiah Maynard to Schaefer, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Flights I-58 Summary Chart, 1947 March 06-1948 December 12 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Flights I-175 Summaries, 1947 September 11-1950 July 13 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Flight #1 Photos, Schenectady, DI Seeding, 1947 September 11; Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Flight #9 Photos, Schenectady, No Identified Operation, 1948 January 22 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Flight #21 Data, Schenectady, DI Pattern Seeding, 1948 April 28 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Flight #21 Photos, Schenectady, DI Pattern Seeding, 1948 April 28 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Flight #23 Data, Cape Cod, DI Seeding- MIT Project, 1948 April 29 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Flight #23 Data, Including Path of B-17, 1948 April 29 (Map-tube 2)
    - Flight #23 Photos and Negatives, 1948 April 29 (Box 1, Folder 22-24)
    - Flight #24 Schenectady, Seeding, Photos, 1948 April 30 (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
    - Flight #27 Photo, Schenectady, DI Pattern Seeding, 1948 May 18 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Flight #27 Photos, 1948 May 18 (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
    - Flight #29 Data, New Jersey Coast, DI Cumulus Seeding, 1948 June 03 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Flight #29 Photos, 1948 June 03 (Box 1, Folder 32-37)
    - Flight #29 Photos, 1948 June 03 (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
    - Flight #33 Data, Lake George, DI Seeding, 1948 July 26 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Flight #33 Photos, 1948 July 26 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Flight #36 Photos, Schenectady Water Seeding, 1948 August 04 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Flight #39 Photos, Schenectady, DI Seeding, 1948 August 10 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Flight #45 Data, Albuquerque, SI and Di Seeding, 1948 October 14 (Box 2, Folder 9-12)
    - Flight #45 Data Charts, 1948 October 14 (Map-tube 2)
    - Flight #45 Photos, 1948 October 14 (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
    - Flight #45 Photos, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Flight #48 Data, Schenectady, DI Seeding Pattern, 1948 November 15 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Flight #50 Data, East of Albany, DI Seeding Pattern, 1948 November 17 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Flight #51 Data, Schenectady, DI Pattern Seeding, 1948 November 23 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Flight #52 Data, Schenectady and Amsterdam, DI Pattern Seeding, 1948 November 24 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Flight #53 Data, Schenectady and Rome, DI Pattern Seeding, 1948 November 24 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Flight #53 Photos, 1948 November 24 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Flight #53 Photos, 1948 November 24 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Flight #54 Data Schenectady, DI Pattern Seeding, 1948 December 01 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Flight #57 Data and Photos, East of Albany, SI and DI Seeding Pattern, 1948 December 21 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Flight #58 Data, Albany Area, DI Seeding Pattern, 1948 December 22 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Flight #59 Data, West of Coxsackie, DI Seeding Pattern, 1949 January 14 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Flight #60 Data and Photos, Puerto Rico, Survey, 1949 February 04 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Flight #60 Photo Slides, 1949 February 04 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Flight #61 Data, Puerto Rico, and Water Seeding, 1949 February 05 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Flight #62 Data, Puerto Rico, Water Seeding, 1949 February 05 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Flight #62 and #63 Photos, 1949 February 05; 1949 February 06 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Flight #64 Data, Puerto Rico, Data Seeding, 1949 February 08 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Flight #64 Photo, 1949 February 08 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Flight #65 Data, Puerto Rico, Survey, 1949 February 08 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Flight #65 Photo, 1949 February 08 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Flight #64 or #65 Photos, 1949 February 08 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Flight #66 Data, Puerto Rico, Survey, 1949 February 10 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Flight #67 and #68 Data, Puerto Rico, 1949 February 11 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Flight #67 Photos, 1949 February 11 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Flights #67-70 Photo Slides, 1949 February 11-1949 February 12 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Flights #67 and #68 Charts- Puerto Rico, 1949 February 11 (Flat-file 1A)
    - Flights #69 and #70 Data, Puerto Rico, Survey, 1949 February 12 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Flight #69 Photos, 1949 February 12 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Flight #70 Data, 1949 February 12 (Map-tube 3)
    - Flight #71 Data, South of Lake Ontario, SI and DI Seeding-Pattern, 1949 March 03 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Flight #72 Data, Sprakers, Temperature Soundings, 1949 March 04 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Flight #73 Data and Photos, Albany, SI Seeding-Pattern, 1949 March 10 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Flight #73 Data, 1949 March 10 (Map-tube 3)
    - Flight #73 Photos, 1949 March 10 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Flight #74 Data, West of Syracuse, DI Seeding, 1949 March 15 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Flight #78 Data, Albany Area, Testing Vortex Thermometer, 1949 March 25 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Flight #79 Data, Schenectady, DI Pattern Seeding, 1949 March 30 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Flight #79 Photos, 1949 March 30 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Flight #80 Data, Albany Area, DI Pattern Seeding, 1949 March 31 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Flight #82 Data, Schenectady, DI Seeding, 1949 April 8 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Flight #83 Data, Schenectady, SI Pattern Seeding, 1949 April 18 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Flight #83 Photos, 1949 April 18 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Flight #85 Data and Photos, Schenectady, Instrument Testing, 1949 April 25 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Flights #88 and #89, Schenectady and Ashokan Reservoir, DI Seeding and Instrument Testing, 1949 May 05 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Flight #89 Photos, 1949 May 05 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Flight #99 Data Ballston Spa, Salt Water Seeding, 1949 June 17 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Flight #99 Photos, 1949 June 17 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Flight #103 Albuquerque, DI Seeding, 1949 July 13 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Flights #103-112, Data Progress Reports, 1949 September (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Flight #104 Data and Photo, Albuquerque, DI and Liquid CO2 and Water Seeding, 1949 July 14 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Flight #105 Data: Vertical Cross-Section Forecast, United Nations Air Forces, 1950 July 15 (Oversized 2, Folder 4)
    - Flight #106 Data, Albuquerque, DI Seeding, 1949 July 16 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Flight #106 Photos, 1949 July 16 (Box 3, Folder 14-15)
    - Flight #107 Data, Albuquerque DI and SI Seeding, 1949 July 18 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Flight #107 Upper Section True Air Plot, 1949 July 18 (Flat-file 1)
    - Flight #108 Data, Albuquerque, DI Seeding, 1949 July 18 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Flight #108 Photos and Negatives, 1949 July 19 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Flight #109 Data, Albuquerque, SI Ground and DI Air Seeding, 1949 July 20 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Flight #109 Photos, 1949 July 20 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Flight #109 and #110 Photo Slides, 1949 July 20-1949 July 21 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Flight #110 Data, Albuquerque, SI Ground and DI Air Seeding, 1949 July 21 (Box 3, Folder 22-23)
    - Flight #110 Photos and Slides, 1949 July 21 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Flight #110 Photos, 1949 July 21 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Flight #110 Upper Section True Air Plot, 1949 July 21 (Flat-file 1)
    - Flight #111 Data, Albuquerque, SI Ground and DI Air Seeding, 1949 July 22 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Flight #112 Data, Albuquerque, SI Ground and DI Air Seeding, 1949 July 23 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Flight #113 Photos, Schoharie Valley, Observing Ground Seeding, 1949 August 24 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Flight #121 Photos, East of Schenectady, DI Seeding; Ground Operation #17, 1949 September 28 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Flight #126 Data, Albany, Observation, 1949 October 24 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Flight #126 Photos, 1949 October 24 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Flight #128 Data, Schenectady, Observation -GO- 39, 1949 November 10 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Flight #133 Data, Schenectady/Indianapolis, Instrument Test and Weather Observation, 1949 November 30 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Flight #134 Data Indianapolis/Schenectady, Instrument Test -GO-47-48, 1949 December 01 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Flight #136 Data and Photos, Schenectady, Snow Replicas and Vortex Thermometer -GO-55, 1949 December 15 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Flight #137 Data, Cape Cod, DI Seeding with MIT, 1949 December 16 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Flight #137 Photos, 1949 December 16 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Flight #138 Data, Mount Washington, SI Detection -GO-63, 1950 January 04 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Flight #138 Photos, 1960 January 04 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Flight #139 Data, Schenectady/ Mount Washington, Instrument Check and DI Seeding, 1950 January 20 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Flight #139 Photos, 1950 January 20 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Flight #140 Data and Photos, Schenectady, Snow Replicas; GO-71, 1950 January 30 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Flight #140 Photos, 1950 January 30 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Flight #142 Data, Schenectady, DI Clear-Air Seeding, 1950 February 03 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Flight # 142 Photos, 1950 February 3 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Flight #143 Data, Schenectady, Snow Replicas/Vortex Thermometer, 1950 February 06 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Flight #143 Photos, 1950 February 10 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Flight #144 Data, Schenectady, Photos/ Snow Replicas, 1950 February 10 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Flight #144 Photos, 1950 February 10 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Flight #146 Data, Schenectady, DI Seeding/ Snow Replicas, 1950 February 28 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Flight #148 Data, Schenectady, Attempted Vapor Trails, 1950 March 03 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Flight #150 Data, Schenectady, Snow Replicas, 2 Small Photos, 1950 March 20 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Flight #151 Data, Schenectady/ Dayton, Weather Reconnaissance, 1950 March 21 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Flight #151 Photos, 1950 March 21 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Flight #152 Data, Dayton/Schenectady, Weather Reconnaissance, 1950 March 22 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Flight #153 Data, Schenectady, Snow Replicas, 1950 April 10 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Flight #153 Photos, 1950 April 10 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Flight #154 Data, Schenectady/ Amsterdam, Sow Replicas, 1950 April 12 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Flight #154 Photos, 1950 April 12 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Flight #155 Data, Schenectady, Observation, 1950 April 18 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Flight #155 and #156 Photos, 1950 April 18; 1950 April 19 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Flight #157 Data, Schenectady/ Boston/ Bangor, etc., SI Seeding, 1950 April 25-1950 April 26 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Flight #157 Surface Charts, 1950 April 26 (Map-tube 4)
    - Flight #159 Data, Schenectady Area, DI Area, DI Clear-Air Seeding, 1950 May 23 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Flight #159 Photos, 1950 May 23 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Flight #160 Data, East Troy and Albany, DI Seeding, 1950 June 06 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Flight #160 Photos, 1950 June 06 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Flight #162 Data, Albuquerque, DI Cumulus Seeding, 1950 June 26 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Flight #163/164 Data, Albuquerque, DI Cumulus Seeding, 1950 June 27 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Flights #163-170 Summary- Draft Letter to Dr. Ference, 1950 July 07 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Flight #165 Data, Albuquerque, DI Cumulus Seeding, 1950 June 28 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Flight #166 Data, Albuquerque, DI Cumulus Seeding, 1950 June 29 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Flight #166 Data, 1950 June 29 (Map-tube 5)
    - Flight #167 Data, Albuquerque, DI Cumulus Seeding, 1950 June 30 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Flight #168 Data, Albuquerque, DI Cumulus Seeding, 1950 July 01 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Flight #168 Data, 1950 July 01 (Map-tube 5)
    - Flight #168 Photo Slides, Albuquerque, DI Cumulus Seeding, 1950 July 01 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Flight #168 Photos, 1950 July 01 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Flight #169 Data, Albuquerque, Tracing Ground SI and DI Seeding, 1950 July 05 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Flight #169 Data, 1950 July 05 (Map-tube 5)